Guide to the Extra-illustrated Life of Nollekens
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- The Monument of The Right Reverend Thomas Newton, D.D. Bishop of Bristol. Published according to the Act of Parliament by John, Francis & Charles Rivington, January 23rd 1787., 1787 January 23; engraving; 16 x 10 cm. (Box 2-192)
  Depiction of Thomas Banks's Monument of Thomas Newton, in St. Mary-le-Bow church, London.
  Engravings; Newton, Thomas, 1704-1782; St. Mary-le-Bow (Church: London, England)
- Untitled engraving of an identified monument., undated; engraving; 17.5 x 12.5 cm. (Box 2-192)
- The Monument erected in St. Paul's Cathedral to the Memory of Captn. Richd. Rundle Burgess Esqr. Voted by Parliament and executed by R. Banks R.A.m 1802 [i.e. Thomas Banks]. Frontspiece to the European Magazine. Vol. 44. Published by J. Asperne, Successor to Mr. Sewell, 32 Cornhill Augt. 1, 1803., 1803 August 1; engraving; 17 x 11 cm. (Box 2-192)
  Engravings; Banks, Thomas, 1735-1805; Burgess, Richard Rundle, Captain; St. Paul's Cathedral (London, England)
- The Alto Relievo in the front of the Shakspeare Gallery, Pall Mall., undated; engraving; 19 x 11 cm. (Box 2-192)
- View from Sir Joshua Reynolds's House, Richmond Hill. Painted by himself & engraved by W. Birch, enamel painter., undated; engraving; 12.5 x 13 cm. (Box 2-195)
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1826 July 4; Standly, Henry Peter; 2 pages; 18.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-198)
  About a sale catalogue of Hogarth prints given to the press on Wednesday, hoping that Smith will have it in time for a meeting.
  Correspondence; Hogarth, William, 1697-1764; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833
- Sir Wm. Chambers. W. Bromley Sculp. 1792., engraving; 13.5 x 10 cm. (Box 2-198)
- Unsigned note regarding John Boydell., undated; 1 page; 7.5 x 12 cm. (Box 2-198)
  "Mr. Bacon waited on Mr. Alderman Boydell to pay his respects to him in being appointed to the succession of the late Mr. Howard. Pall Mall. May 18th.
  Correspondence; Boydell, John, 1720-1804
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1819 October 22; Thornton, E. N.; 3 pages; 22.5 x 19 cm. (Box 2-198)
  About a story of Queen Henrietta at Tyburn and its appearance in Isaac D'Israeli's Curiosities of Literature.
  Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Henrietta Maria, Queen, consort of Charles I, King of England, 1609-1669; Disraeli, Isaac, 1766-1848
- Thomas Earle of Arundell & Surrey; Earle Marshall & Lord High Steward of England, etc. Published 1872 by W. Richardson Yorke House, Strand., engraving; 14 x 9.5 cm. (Box 2-198)
  Portrait of Thomas Howard, Earl of Arundel.
- Advertisement for Joshua Ward's medicines., 1774 June 24; 1 page; 5 x 6 cm. (Box 2-198)
  Medicine -- Great Britain; Clippings; Ward, Joshua, 1685-1761
- Grecian harvest home. Barry pinxt. Clint sc., undated (Box 2-200)
  engraving; 11 x 13 cm.
- The Thames. Barry pinxt. Clint sc., undated; engraving; 12 x 13 cm. (Box 2-200)
- Orpheus singing his divine poems. Barry pinxt. Clint sc., undated; engraving; 12 x 13 cm. (Box 2-200)
- The Society for the Encouragement of the Arts. Barry pinxt. J. Mitan sculp., undated; engraving; 12 x 13 cm. (Box 2-200)
- Richard Wilson. Painted by Raphael Mings. Engraved by Charles Pye. London. Pub. for the proprietor. September 1822. Proof., 1822 September; engraving; 15.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-202)
- Burney. H. Adlard sculp., undated; engraving; 12 x 10 cm. (Box 2-202)
  Portrait of Adlard Burney.
  Engravings; Burney, Charles, 1726-1814
- The Late Joseph Nollikens Esqr. R.A. Engraved by C.S. Taylor from an original painting. By Sir W. Beechey R.A. London. Published for the new European Magazine, by John Letts Junr. 32, Cornhill, 2nd June, 1823., 1823 June 2; engraving; 21.5 x 14 cm. (Box 2-202)
- Autograph notes by Molesworth Phillilps., 1782; Upcott, William, 1779-1845; Phillips, Molesworth, 1755-1832; 3 pages; 18.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-203)
  About a conversation between Charles Burney and Joseph Nollekens; annotated by William Upcott (to the effect that the writer was on one of Cook's voyages).
  Correspondence; Burney, Charles, 1726-1814; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Untitled view of Orange Street Chapel, Sunday & infant's school, established 1812., undated; engraving; 14 x 10 cm. (Box 2-204)
- Captain Thomas Coram. Hogarth pinxt. T. Cook & Son sculpt. Published by Longman, Hurst, Rees & Orme, March 1st 1808., 1808 March 1; engraving; 22.5 x 14 cm. (Box 2-213)
  Portrait of Captain Thomas Coram.
  Engravings; Coram, Thomas, 1668?-1751
- Envelope fragment from John Brownlow to Joseph Nollekens., 1808 January 14; Brownlow, John Cust, 1st Earl, 1779-1853; 1 page; 8 x 13 cm. (Box 2-208)
- Autographed note by Isaac D'Isreali., 1796 February 20; Disraeli, Isaac, 1766-1848; 1 page; 5.5 x 18 cm. (Box 2-209)
  About delivery of D'Isreali's book :"To deliver Dr. Wolcot one copy of my Miscellany".
- Residence of John Hoole, the translator of Tasso & Ariosto. Great Queen Street. Lincolns Inn Fields., undated; engraving; 16 x 10 cm. (Box 2-212)
  View of residence of John Hoole.
  Engravings; Hoole, John, 1727-1803
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1827 August 10; Packer, William; 1 page; 23 x 18.5 cm. (Box 2-214)
  About Lord Farnborough's letter.
  Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Hogarth, William, 1697-1764; Long, Charles, 1761-1838
- Untitled portrait of Nathaniel Smith., undated; lithograph; 12.5 x 9 cm. (Box 2-216)
  Engravings; Smith, N. (Nathaniel), 1738?-1809
- Handwritten note granting Mr. T. Philipe permission to view a gallery., 1802 April 2; Smith, N. (Nathaniel), 1738?-1809; 1 page; 8.5 x 13 cm. (Box 2-216)
- Marriage a la Mode. Hogarth pinxt. T. Cook & Son sc. Published by Longman Hurst Rees & Orme. July 1st. 1808., 1808 July 1; engraving; 14.5 x 17.5 cm. (Box 2-222)
- Letter to Ozias Humphry., 1771 July 30; Payne, James, 1717?-1789; 1 page; 22 x 19 cm. (Box 2-224)
  Asking for his company tomorrow.
  Correspondence; Humphry, Ozias, 1742-1810
- Sir R.T. Wilson. Knt. M.P., undated; engraving; 22.5 x 14 cm. (Box 2-225)
  Portrait of Sir Robert Thomas Wilson.
  Lithographs; Wilson, Robert Thomas, Sir, 1777–1849
- Letter, apparently to John Thomas Smith., 1821 July 30; Musgrave, William; 2 pages; 25 x 20 cm. (Box 2-228)
  About portraits of Dr. Misaubin. Also mentions a gentleman who lived on gin for many years and who was the model for Hogarth's Quack Doctor in the Marriage-a-la-Mode.
  Correspondence; Hogarth, William, 1697-1764; Misaubin, Jean, 1673-1734; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833
- The Right Honourable Charles Abbot, Baron Colchester. London, Published for the European Magazine, by J. Asperne, 32, Cornhill 1st. Octr. 1817. Engraved by H. Meyer; from an original painting by S. Drummond Esq. R.A., 1817 October 1; engraving; 19.5 x 13 cm. (Box 2-237)
  Portrait of Charles Abbot.
  Engravings; Abbot, Charles, Baron Colchester, 1757-1829
- Joseph Nollekens, Esq. R.A. From an original picture by F. Abbot, in his own possession. Drawn by W. Evans, engraved by J. Vendramini., undated; engraving; 27 x 20 cm. (Box 2-244)
- The Late Joseph Nollikens Esqr. R.A. Engraved by C.S. Taylor from an original painting by Sir W. Beechey R.A. London. Published for the New Eruopean Magazine by John Letts Junr. 32, Cornhill, 2nd June 1823., 1823 June 2; engraving; 19 x 13 cm. (Box 2-254)
- The Late Joseph Nollikens Esqr. R.A. Engraved by C.S. Taylor from an original painting by Sir W. Beechey R.A. London. Published for the New Eruopean Magazine by John Letts Junr. 32, Cornhill, 2nd June 1823., 1823 June 2; engraving; 17.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-254)
  Portrait of Joseph Nollekens (2nd copy).
- Nollekens. Engraved by Scriven, Historical Enbgraver to His Majesty., undated; engraving; 19 x 10 cm. (Box 2-254)
  Portrait of Nollekens.
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1829 January 3; Wilson, Thomas, 1773-1858; 2 pages; 22.5 x 19 cm. (Box 2-254)
  About paying for his copy of the book on Joseph Nollekens.
- Advertisement for The Provok'd Wife, a play (by John Vanbrugh) to be performed at Covent Garden, Nov. 1, 1777., 1777 November 1; 1 page; 11 x 6.5 cm. (Box 2-277)
  Clippings; Covent Garden Theatre; Vanbrugh, John, Sir, 1664-1726
- A Pretty Copy!, undated; aquatint; 14.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-280)
  Portrait of Isaac Gossett.
  Aquatints; Gossett, Isaac, 1745-1812
- J. Walker. Painted by Jas. Barry. Engraved by R. Hicks. London, 1834., engraving; 17 x 12 cm. (Box 2-282)
  Portrait of John Walker.
  Engravings; Walker, John, 1732-1807
- Advertisement for Othello at the Theatre Royal, Covent Garden., 1777 November 1; 1 page; 10 x 6.5 cm. (Box 2-290)
  Clippings; Covent Garden Theatre
- Advertisement for The Merchant of Venice at the Theatre Royal in Covent Garden., 1780 November 30; 1 page; 12.5 x 6.5 cm. (Box 2-290)
- Mr. Macklin in the character of Shylock. Act 4th Scene 2d., undated; engraving; 9.5 x 8 cm. (Box 2-290)
  Engravings; Macklin, Charles, 1697?-1797
- Advertisement for The Man of the World at the Theatre-Royal, Covent-Garden., 1784 January 29; 1 page; 14.5 x 7.5 cm. (Box 2-290)
- Man of the World. Sir Pertinax - What is the Matter Wi' Ye, Mon? Act V. Scene I. Painted by Singleton. Published by Longman & Co. March, 1816. Engraved by C. Heath., 1816 March; engraving; 15 x 10 cm. (Box 2-290)
  Depiction of a scene from Man of the World.
- Advertisement for The Refusal at the Theatre-Royal in Covent-Garden., 1752 January 14; 1 page; 11 x 8 cm. (Box 2-290)
- The Refusal. Mr. Macklin as Sir Gilbert Wrangle. De Wilde Pinxt. Thornthwaite sculp. London, Printed for J. Bell, British Library, Strand, Novr. 3 1792., 1792 November 3; engraving; 14 x 9.5 cm. (Box 2-290)
- Receipt for for sum paid to R. Phillips., 178- June 21; 1 page; 8 x 19 cm. (Box 2-290)
  Receipt
- Saml Rogers. Engraved by B. Holl., undated; engraving; 15.5 x 10.5 cm. (Box 2-295)
- John Earl of Bute. First Lord of the Treasury. From an original picture by Ramsay. Published May 1, 1802, by Cadell & Davies, Strand., 1802 May 1; engraving; 16.5 x 9.5 cm. (Box 2-296)
  John Stuart, Earl of Bute.
  Engravings; Bute, John Stuart, Earl of, 1713-1792
- George Keate Esqr. J. Pott pinxt. J.K. Sherwin sculpt., undated; engraving; 17 x 10 cm. (Box 2-301)
  Portrait of George Keate Esqr.
  Engravings; Keate, George, 1729-1797
- Thomas Mortimer, Esqr. Sr. W. Beechey pinxt. Ridley sculp., undated; engraving; 14 x 10.5 cm. (Box 2-300)
  Portrait of Thomas Mortimer.
  Engravings; Mortimer, Thomas, 1730-1810
- Advertisement for Collins's Morning Brush, a series of theatrical sketches., 1788 March 26; 1 page; 6 x 7 cm. (Box 2-302)
- Advertisement for performance of Collins's Brush, "comprising a copious diversity of histrionic sketches, dramatic incidents, theatrical blunders, and grotesque examples of stage effect, with a variety of new and original songs"., 1792 March 31; 1 page; 14 x 7 cm. (Box 2-302)
- Advertisement for Collins's Evening Brush., 1789 March 30; 1 page; 10 x 7 cm. (Box 2-302)
- Letter from Joseph (?) Deare to his uncle., 1832 October 15; 1 page; 11 x 18 cm. (Box 2-304)
  Concluding portion of a letter to his uncle, written in French.
  Correspondence; Deare, Joseph, 1803-1835
- Constantine's Arch. London, Pubd. March 1, 1796 by J. Merigot, No. 28 Haymarket., 1796 March 1; aquatint engraving; 18 x 24.5 cm. (Box 2-319)
  View of the Arch of Constantine (Rome).
  Arch of Constantine (Rome, Italy); Aquatints
- Untitled portrait(probably Thomas Major)., undated; engraving; 16.5 x 12 cm. (Box 2-336)
  Engravings; Major, Thomas, 1720-1799
- Signed receipt to Ozias Humphry for his whole stock of crayons etc. Also endorsed by William Upcott with a note about the other signatory, James Bishop, Humphry's footman., 1795 December 5; Upcott, William, 1779-1845; Morland, Henry Robert, circa 1716–1797; 1 page; 8.5 x 19 cm. (Box 2-338)
  Receipt; Humphry, Ozias, 1742-1810
- Ellis Gamble, Goldsmith, at the Golden Angel in Cranbourn-Street, Leicester-Fields. Makes, Buys & Sells all sorts of Plate, Rings & Jewells., undated; engraving; 22.5 x 15 cm. (Box 2-347)
  Engraved trade card for Ellis Gamble, goldsmith.
  Engravings; Goldsmiths -- Great Britain; Trade cards (advertising); Gamble, Ellis
- Letter to John Thomas Smith about the sale of Baker's books and another print sale., 1825 June 10; Standly, Henry Peter; 3 pages; 18.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-350)
- The Author's Benefit Pasquin. At ye theatre in ye Hay-market. Tuesday April 24th. W. Hogarth, A.M. Ireland fe., undated; engraving; 13 x 14 cm. (Box 2-352)
  Advertisement for the Author's Benefit at Haymarket.
- Untitled etching. J. Barry Int. To J.T. Smith Esq. this etching is inscribed by his most grateful pupil, C.E. Dyer (?), June 11, 1807., 1807 June 11; Dyer, C. E.; etching; 19.5 x 16 cm. (Box 2-358)
- The Diagorides Victors at Olympia [and] Elysium or the State of Final Retribution. Barry Pinxt. J. Mitan sculp., undated; 2 engravings; 10.5 x 22 cm. each. (Box 2-359)
- Edmund Burke. Engraved by W. Read from the original by Sir Joshua Reynolds. London. Published by Richard Bentley 1836., engraving; 19 x 14 cm. (Box 2-364)
  Portrait of Edmund Burke.
  Engravings; Burke, Edmund, 1729-1797
- Three untitled engravings depicting the arms of Ozias Humphry, etc., undated; 3 engravings; 8 x 7 cm.; 9 x 6.5 cm.; 7.5 x 6 cm. (Box 2-366)
  The third engraving depicts John Humphry on a horse.
  Engravings; Humphry, Ozias, 1742-1810
- Os. Humphry, miniature painter. From an original drawing by P. Falconet. B. Reading scut. Pubd. by E. Jeffrey, Pall Mall, 1792., lithograph; 18 x 15 cm. (Box 2-366)
  Portrait of Ozias Humphry.
- Two letter fragments with signatures, one by Ozias Humphry and one by his father., 1758 September 1; Humphry, George, d. 1759; Humphry, Ozias, 1742-1810; 2 letter fragments; 5.5 x 17.5 cm.; 5.5 x 11 cm. (Box 2-366)
  The first fragment signed "Your most humble servant, Geo. Humphry" with annotated note by W. Upcott. The second signed "Ozias Humphry Honiton Septr. 1st. 1758.
- Letter to William Upcott., 1807 February 6; Humphry, Ozias, 1742-1810; 1 page; 20 x 16 cm. (Box 2-370)
  Introducing Mr. (Joseph Michael) Gandy, an architect and member of the Royal Academy.
  Correspondence; Gandy, Joseph Michael, 1771-1843; Upcott, William, 1779-1845
- Letter to Mr. (James?) Payne., 1771 September 7; Humphry, Ozias, 1742-1810 (Box 2-372)
  1 page; 8.5 x 18 cm.
  Correspondence; Payne, James, 1717?-1789
- "Lines written by Mr. [Thomas?] Maurice on Mr. West expiring with his pencil in his hand.", undated; 1 page; 17 x 11 cm. (Box 2-386)
  West, Benjamin, 1738-1820; Maurice, Thomas, 1754-1824
- Handwritten invitation to the funeral of George Henry Harlow, 12 February 1819, addressed to Joseph Nollekens., 1819 February 12; 1 page; 7 x 11 cm. (Box 2-421)
  Funeral rites and ceremonies -- Great Britain; Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; Harlow, George Henry, 1787-1819
- Henry Fuseli, from a sketch by Sir Thomas Lawrence (from handwritten note)., undated; engraving; 16.5 x 12 cm. (Box 2-422)
- St. John. Fuseli delint. T. Holloway direxit., undated; engraving; 19 x 13 cm. (Box 2-422)
  Portrait of Saint John.
- Drawn from memory after a real scene in the Hospital of S. Spirito at Rome ... Fuseli delint. Holloway sc. Published as the act directs by T. Holloway: 20 Oct. 1791., 1791 October 20; engraving; 13.5 x 18 cm. (Box 2-422)
- Dies Praeteritos! Frontispiece to Vol. III. Sharp fc. Published Novr. 1 1795 by Cadell & Davies, Strand., 1795 November 1; engraving; 14 x 10 cm. (Box 2-422)
- Letter to an unidentified recipient., 1803 February 28; Richards, John Inigo, 1731-1810; 1 page; 11 x 20 cm. (Box 2-432)
  Announcing that Fuseli will give his second lecture at the Royal Academy this evening, 28 February 1803.
  Correspondence; Fuseli, Henry, 1741-1825; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Hy. Fuseli. From a painting by H.G. Harlow, & Engraved by E. Scriven. Historical engraver to His Majesty George IVth. Library of the Fine Arts, 1831., engraving; 16.5 x 12 cm. (Box 2-434)
- Lavater. Drawing by H. Pfen. Engraved by J. Hopwood. Published by James Robins & Co. Ivy Lane, London. Aug. 1, 1828., 1828 August 1; engraving; 17.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-438)
  Portrait of Johann Caspar Lavater.
  Engravings; Lavater, Johann Caspar, 1741-1801
- Letter to Ozias Humphry., undated; Fuseli, Henry, 1741-1825; 1 page; 6.5 x 9.5 cm. (Box 2-440)
  Saying that he cannot dine with Humphry. With autograph address panel in Henry Fuseli's hand, annotated by Upcott.
- John Flaxman. Engraved by R. Woodman. From the original picture by John Jackson, in the possession of the Right Hon: Lord Dover. Under the Superintendence of the Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge., undated; engraving; 19 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-442)
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1830 April 7; Flaxman, Mary Anne, 1768-1833; 1 page; 19 x 11 cm. (Box 2-442)
  Asking to call for his opinion on an unspecified matter.
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1819 January 29; Knight, Richard Payne, 1751-1824; 1 page; 14 x 12 cm. (Box 2-442)
  Asking Smith to show the Rembrandt etchings to Mr. Schippers (?), a "respectable inhabitant and public functionary of Bruxelles."
- From the Monument in Winchester Cathedral, raised by subscription of the Wickhamists, and executed by John Flaxman. R.A. London. Published May 1, 1806 by Cadell & Davies., 1806 May 1; engraving; 20 x 13 cm. (Box 2-444)
  View of a monument in Winchester Cathedral.
  Engravings; Winchester Cathedral
- William Cowper Esq. Engraved by Cooper from the original painting byt Abbott. Published June 5, 1824, by Henry Colburn & Simpkin & Marshall., 1824 June 5; engraving; 16.5 x 9.5 cm. (Box 2-446)
- John Flaxman. Derby pinxt. Thomson sculp. London. Published for the proprietors of the European Magazine by Lupton Relfe 13, Cornhill, June 1823., 1823 June; engraving; 17 x 13.5 cm. (Box 2-454)
- Westminster Abbey. Lord Mansfield's Monument, The View Looking Across the Choir. To Francis Freeling, Esqr. F.S. A. Secretary to the General Post Office. This plate with feelings of respect and gratitude is inscribed by J.P. Neale. Drawn by J.P. Neal. Engraved by W. Woolnoth. London, Published Mar. 1, 1817, by Longman & Co. Paternoster Row, & J.P. Neal, Bennett Stt. Blackfriars Road. Printed by Cox & Barnett., 1817 March 1; engraving; 25.5 x 18 cm. (Box 2-454)
  View of the monument of William Murray, Earl of Mansfield, in Westminster Abbey.
  Engravings; Mansfield, William Murray, Earl of, 1705-1793; Westminster Abbey
- Medal won by the Committee at the Dinner. John Phillip Kemble ... Published by John Miller; Bow Street, Covent Garden, August 1817., 1817 August; engraving; 18 x 10 cm. (Box 2-456)
  Illustration of medal given to John Phillip Kemble.
  Engravings; Kemble, John Phillip, 1757-1823
- Letter to Mr. Gonig (or Going?), in Italian., 1818 March 3; Pistrucci, Benedetto, 1783-1855; 1 page; 14.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-460)
  Writing that he has been ill for the past week and has had to call the doctor.
- Fragment of an antique statue of Ceres, found in the Ruins of Eleusis and now placed in the public library at Cambridge., undated; engraving; 26 x 20 cm. (Box 2-462)
- Six small engravings, some of which are perhaps by William Blake and others perhaps after his drawings., undated; 6 engravings (Box 2-472)
  Engravings; Blake, William, 1757-1827
- William Hayley, Esqr. Engraved by Ridley from a picture by Geo: Romney, Esqr., undated; engraving; 14 x 11 cm. (Box 2-472)
- Letter to an unidentified man., 1815 February 22; Payne, Thomas, 1752-1831; 1 page; 22 x 18 cm. (Box 2-472)
  The bookseller, writing on behalf of Payne & Foss, requests payment.
  Correspondence; Payne and Foss
- Letter to an unidentified man., undated; Worthington, William Henry, circa 1795-circa 1839; 3 pages; 21.5 x 18.5 cm. (Box 2-472)
  About a remarkable dog called Trimmer, belonging to a Mr. Monk of 17 Pear Tree Street, St. Lukes. Also includes fragment of page with Worthington's address.
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1811 November 23; Camden, John Jeffreys Pratt, Marquis of, 1759-1840; 2 pages; 18 x 12 cm. (Box 2-472)
  About the bust of Lord Castlereagh.
  Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; Castlereagh, Robert Stewart, Viscount, 1769-1822
- An article titled "Modern Monumental Brasses.", 5 pages; 23.5 x 18 cm. (Box 2-472)
- Mademoiselle de Beaumont, or the Chevalier D'Eon. Female Minister Plenipo. Capt. of dragoons &c. &c., 1777 September; engraving; 18 x 10.5 cm. (Box 2-472)
  Portrait of the Chevalier D'Eon. Accompanied by article "Chevalier D'Eon's Sale" about the end of the sale of the Chevalier's books and manuscripts.
  Clippings; Engravings; Eon de Beaumont, Charles Geneviève Louis Auguste André Timothée d', 1728-1810
- Humorous Sketches of Skeletons. Engaged in the various sciences. Drawn by H. Heathcote Russell as a companion to the skeletons copied from the Long Wall at Brentford. London, Published 3d June 1830 by S. Gans. 15 Southampton Street, Strand., 1830 June 3; engraving; 25 x 45 cm. (Box 2-472)
  Humorous sketches of skeletons engaged in "Singing", "Dancing", "Music", "Oratory", "Painting", and "Sculpture".
- Printed invitation to meet the president and members of the Royal Academy the following Monday. From John Richards, R.A. Secretary., 1795 January 12; Richards, John Inigo, 1731-1810; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; 2 pages; 22.5 x 18.5 cm. (Box 2-472)
  With a detailed architectural sketch by Nollekens on the back for a proposed monument, giving measurements.
  Correspondence; Graphite drawings; Monuments -- Great Britain; Royal Academy of Arts (Great Britain)
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., undated; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; Manners, Catherine Rebecca, Lady, 1766 or 7-1852; 2 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box 2-472)
  Arranging to meet him. With a sketch by Nollekens on verso of a design for a monument.
  Monuments -- Great Britain; Graphite drawings; Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Printed invitation to meet the president and rest of the council of the Royal Academy on the 28th of February at 3 o'clock to inspect the progress of the new exhibition room. From Henry Howard, R.A. Secretary., 1811 February 27; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; Howard, Henry, 1769-1847; 2 pages; 20 x 28 cm. (Box 2-472)
  With sketches by Joseph Nollekens on the verso showing detailed designs with measurements of two monuments, one for a Mr. Bagge dated May 1st 1811.
  Royal Academy of Arts (Great Britain); Graphite drawings; Monuments -- Great Britain; Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1828 November 19; Twopenny, William, 1797-1873; 1 page; 19 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-472)
  Asking "Can you tell me where the widow of Blake the artist lives?". The writer is presumably to be identified both with the William Twopenny referred to as pupil-master to Charles Winston and the man of this name who was a collector and who was the principal patron of the artist John Wykenham Archer.
  Correspondence; Blake, William, 1757-1827; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., undated; Varley, John, 1778-1842; 1 page; 10.5 x 9.5 cm. (Box 2-479)
  Checking on the name of a subscriber, possibly Mr. Packer.
- Death's Door. La porte du tombeau. Blake. Normand fils., undated; engraving; 16 x 9.5 cm. (Box 2-491)
  Outline engraving reproducing William Blake's "Death's door", accompanied by a short text explaining the work.
- Death of the Strong Wicked Man. Mort D'Un Rèprouvè. Blake. Normand fils., undated (Box 2-494)
  Outline engraving reproducing William Blake's "Death of the strong wicked man", accompanied by a short text explaining the work.
  engraving; 10 x 12 cm.
- Letter to William Behnes., 1827 July 17; Kerrich, Richard Edward, 1801-1872; 3 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box 3-a)
  About putting up a monument to Joseph Nollekens's memory, in Paddington Church, with design suggestions by Kerrich. William Behnes was the eventual designer of the Nollekens monument. The letter includes a pen and ink sketch of the monument, probably by Kerrich.